<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Portfolio</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Portfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 22:55:05 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>My Semester in Computational Biology</title>
      <link>/blog/python-for-data-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/python-for-data-science/</guid>
      <description>This is my last semester at UT Austin, and I would say that the data science skills I have learned will be useful going forward. This fall, I will be attending the Long School of Medicine at UT Health San Antonio, and I will definitely be looking into becoming involved in research. Maybe I could woo a professor by offering to help with data analysis, who knows!
For most of the computational biology course, we focused on learning R for data analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 22:55:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/</guid>
      <description>Projects Here are some projects I have recently completed:
  Exploratory Data Analysis with Tidyverse Tools
  Modeling, Testing, and Classification
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SDS348 Project 1</title>
      <link>/project1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project1/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionThe two datasets I chose are “country_lit” and “country_MFI,” both of which were found on Kaggle. Country_MFI contains infant mortality rate, fertility rate, and national income per capita for every country over the years 1970-2013. It also has the region of each country. Country_lit contains the literacy rates of every country, as well as the percentage of their economy accounted for by agriculture.
Part of the reason I decided to examine these datasets was to see which parts of the world were the most in the early phases of development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SDS348 Project 2</title>
      <link>/project2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project2/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionThis dataset contains information about 303 patients and is focused on conditions of the heart. The variables analyzed were age, sex (1=male, 2=female), cp(chest pain, 0=asymptomatic, 1=atypical angina, 2=non-anginal pain, 3=typical angina), fbs (fasting blood sugar, 1= &amp;gt;120 mg/dl, 0= &amp;lt;120mg/dl), restecg (resting electrocardiographic results, 0=left ventricular hypertrophy, 1=normal, 2=ST-T wave abnormality), exang (exercised enduced angina, 1=yes, 0=no), and finally, target (1=disease, 0=no disease). I altered the dataset some before analysis, first switching the 1 and 0 values of target, as 1 initially corresponded to ‘no disease’, which is counterintuitive.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>